{
  "reference_number": "11331",
  "clauses": [
    {
      "question": "1. What process should the Government use to set a new emissions reduction target in legislation?",
      "question_index": 0,
      "answer": "The Government sets a 2050 target in legislation now",
      "answer_index": 0,
      "notes": "We don't have time to keep pondering, we need to send a strong signal that we intend to rise to this challenge and the experts can\n advise us on the how."
    },
    {
      "question": "2. If the Government sets a 2050 target now, which is the best target for New Zealand?",
      "question_index": 1,
      "answer": "Net Zero Emissions - Net zero emissions across all greenhouse gases by 2050",
      "answer_index": 1,
      "notes": "Even this target may not be ambitious enough given the current science. We will only develop the technology needed if we force\n ourselves to focus on that. It is not good enough to say \"we will include methane once we know how to reduce it\" We need to include\n\n methane so that we are motivated to figure out how to reduce it."
    },
    {
      "question": "3. How should New Zealand meet its targets?",
      "question_index": 2,
      "answer": "Domestic emissions reductions only (including from new forest planting)",
      "answer_index": 7,
      "notes": "Too much possibility of abuse from international credits. It could create a sense for business that we have a \"get out of jail free\" card\n and minimise their focus and commitment to reducing our domestic emissions."
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Should the Zero Carbon Bill allow the 2050 target to be revised if circumstances change?",
      "question_index": 3,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "The only changes we should be allowed to make are for the target to become more ambitious, that is to reduce our emmissions\n\n below net zero, toward gross zero."
    },
    {
      "question": "5. The Government proposes that three emissions budgets of five years each (i.e. covering the next 15 years) be in place at any given time. Do you agree with this proposal?",
      "question_index": 15,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "2050 is too far away for most people to think about. It is essential that businesses and households have specific medium-term\n guidance about what the price of carbon will be to inform their investment decisions."
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Should the Government be able to alter the last emissions budget (i.e. furthest into the future)?",
      "question_index": 4,
      "answer": "No - emissions budgets should not be able to be changed",
      "answer_index": 9,
      "notes": "This will reduce the usefulness of the budgets for predictability."
    },
    {
      "question": "7. Should the Government have the ability to review and adjust the second emissions budget within a specific range under exceptional circumstances? See p36 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 5,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "8. Do you agree with the considerations we propose that the Government and the Climate Change Commission take into account when advising on and setting budgets? See p44 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 6,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "Public borrowing to invest in climate transition should be treated differently to other types of borrowing when assessing the fiscal\nimpact. Borrowing more is bad for future generations. But not dealing with climate change is worse for future generations. If anything\n\ncan justify higher rates of public debt, it is responding to climate change."
    },
    {
      "question": "9. Should the Zero Carbon Bill require Governments to set out plans within a certain timeframe to achieve the emissions budgets?",
      "question_index": 7,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "It seems like there is basically no point to the budgets if you don't require a specific government plan to achieve it."
    },
    {
      "question": "11. The Government has proposed that the Climate Change Commission advises on and monitors New Zealand's progress towards its goals. Do you agree with these functions? See p42 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 9,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "12. What role do you think the Climate Change Commission should have in relation to the New Zealand Emissions Trading Scheme (NZ ETS)?",
      "question_index": 10,
      "answer": "Makes decisions itself in respect of the number of units available in the NZ ETS",
      "answer_index": 10,
      "notes": "The less politicians have to do with setting carbon price the better. Makes the issue less about political points scoring."
    },
    {
      "question": "14. Do you think the Zero Carbon Bill should cover adapting to climate change?",
      "question_index": 12,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "15. The Government has proposed a number of new functions to help us adapt to climate change. Do you agree with the proposed functions? See p47 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 13,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "16. Should we explore setting up a targeted adaptation reporting power that could see some organisations share information on their exposure to climate change risks?",
      "question_index": 14,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "Tough call. The information would be good to have but you have to balance that against the commercial sensitivity of that information.\nI think if you can find a way to do this where the information remains confidential to those who need it to shape adaptation policy that\n\nthe public benefit outweighs the intrusion.\n\n\n\n\n You have elected to withhold your personal details from publication."
    }
  ]
}
